♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Ibyang] What did Aunt Cita say?
[Ame] We won't be with her anymore.
She's gone.
PREVIOUSLY
[Janine] I feel guilty.
- Were you with Atoy?
- [Janine] No.
[Ibyang] You should have brought
Sister Tonet to Tatoy.
Maybe she wouldn't have been
in an accident.
Maybe she'd still be alive!
You're so selfish!
[Emerson, in English] Freak accident?
The scaffolding fell on her?
[Red] What's your problem? Tonet's dead.
It's my first time killing someone.
[Martina, in English]
I've never done that!
You killed her for a good reason.
[Mercado] What's this for, Padua?
[Atoy] Just a personal mission, sir.
My assistant, Tonet…
I suspect what happened to her
wasn't an accident.
[Atoy] What did the man and woman
who accused her look like?
[security guard]
Sir, the man was tall, fair-skinned.
And the woman
was beautiful, had round eyes.
They said they were married.
[Atoy] Can I see that?
[security guard]
The computer system crashed
when the fire alarm went off.
All the recorded files
from that day were erased.
Unless someone deleted them.
[Dmitri, in English] Wait.
What happened to your bag?
[Martina] I just noticed this now.
[music fades]
[crickets chirping]
What happened to that rock stud?
It doesn't just come off easily.
[anxious music playing]
[in English] Not unless…
[grunting]
Could I have left it there?
Is this what you're looking for?
[music swells]
[frantic music playing]
[screaming]
[panicked breathing]
[Red] Hon. Hon!
- [gasping]
- [Red groans]
[mysterious music playing]
- [in English] What's wrong?
- [gasping]
- Tonet stabbed me!
- [Red groans]
[in English] Right here!
[in English] Why is she in my dreams now?
You're just thinking about it too much.
[sighs]
What can I do?
‪[sighs]
[in English] You know what?
Maybe you should go to the wake tomorrow.
Go with Audrey.
[in English] No. That's not
gonna help me get over it.
Yes, I know. But… get some news there.
Maybe she told someone else what she knew.
Maybe they still want to investigate
her death, right?
Find out what's on their mind.
Find out what's on Atoy's mind.
[in English] Why-- Why Atoy?
[in English] He's a tracker.
So, he's like a spy.
He probably has another theory
about Tonet's death.
It's better that we know already,
before he starts to suspect.
[rousing music playing]
[sauve theme music playing]
[clacking]
[music fades]
[man] My condolences.
[woman] Sir, our condolences.
[muffled chattering]
'Son.
Emerson, my condolences.
Do you need anything? Have you eaten?
- [Emerson] Yes.
- [Paldo] Bro.
Here's your favorite pares,
from Brother Kurt.
Condolences, Emerson.
We also offer our condolences.
Bro, a tight hug.
[somber music playing]
Thank you.
Emerson, we know you're alone now.
But we won't let you feel alone.
If we can help with anything,
just let us know.
What do you need?
[melancholic music playing]
I need to have…
formal clothes made for Tonet.
She doesn't have anything for the burial.
[knock on door]
[Siony] Emerson?
Bro, here's the fabric you need.
Do you need anything else?
Nothing more. Thank you.
We're here for you.
[sentimental music playing]
There's only one person…
important to me that I don't want to lose.
Who?
- You! You're so silly.
- [laughs]
- Who else! Who else would it be?
All right.
Okay, okay, okay.
So dramatic! You're so dramatic.
- It's fine.
- There's global warming.
This is the first time
we've hugged like this.
Okay, okay, okay.
[in English] I love you too.
I love you too.
[sentimental music playing]
- [Peping] Emerson.
- [Emerson sniffs]
- [man] 'Son, here.
- Thank you.
Here.
[melancholic music playing]
Are you okay?
I'm fine now. I'm okay, thank you.
[inaudible]
[music fades]
Bro. Emerson.
You haven't eaten yet.
I'm fine.
[melancholic music playing]
I brought you coffee.
I'll put it here.
[Kurt] This is Bicol Express.
That's my secret recipe.
[Emerson] I'm fine.
Just put it there.
[sewing machine whirring]
It's beautiful, Emerson!
Tonet will surely love this.
[melodramatic music playing]
Too bad she won't see what I made.
[Emerson sobs]
I didn't even make her anything.
But at least…
At least she can still wear…
wear… [sobs]
what I sewed.
[softly] You made something beautiful.
[sobs, then sighs]
[chuckles softly]
[music fades]
Now I understand how you felt when…
you made clothes
for Sir Delfin, for his wake.
[melancholic music playing]
Somehow, I'm happy that I made…
[voice breaks] I made a dress for Tonet.
I just--
[sobs]
I just didn't know it would be like this…
That I'd be making her burial clothes.
[sobbing]
It hurts so much.
It hurts.
Because just when we got reunited,
she was taken from me right away.
[sobbing]
[Emerson] It hurts.
Bro, God has a reason why
she was taken from you so soon.
[sobs, then sighs]
I suspect…
Tonet's death wasn't an accident.
- [mysterious music playing]
- [dramatic sting]
What do you mean?
Was there foul play?
It seems someone else was there.
Maybe a woman, but…
I'm not sure.
How can you say that?
[suspicious music playing]
Because I went back to the place
where she died.
I smelled the perfume of…
[music swells]
…a woman who…
[Atoy] I found a piece of evidence
that she might have left behind.
[music swells]
[birds chirping]
[somber music playing]
[Tonet] Don't worry.
I'll take care of you.
I really hate seeing you cry.
Because you know, I love you so much!
[dramatic sting]
Ibyang, help me fix this.
This is heavy.
Ibyang, are you okay?
Ibyang?
I already miss Sister Tonet.
Me too.
What hurts more is that I was so useless
the last time we talked.
I wish I had good memories with her.
What did you and Sister Tonet talk about
before she passed?
[Ibyang] Please don't close
your eyes, okay?
- Don't close your eyes, okay? [sobbing]
- [gasping]
Sister, don't close your eyes.
You-- You have lunch with Brother Emerson!
Ja… Janine…
Janine…
Janine… Janine. She's not…
She's not-- She's not…
Hmm.
She mentioned Janine.
She said, "She's not…"
[suspicious music playing]
She's not what?
That's all. Then she lost consciousness.
Of all people, why was Janine
the last person she thought of
before she died?
[mysterious music playing]
Is this really the wake?
It should've been at a funeral home,
so there's air conditioning.
[in English] Will you shut it, Martina?
[in English] Nobody asked you to be here.
[in English] I'm just saying.
It would've been better there, right?
[in English] Mom, please be nice.
I know Tonet, okay?
We're not close, but we have history.
[in English] Can you guys give me a break?
I won't do anything to her.
[in English] Come on, Gavin. Let's go.
[indistinct chattering]
[man] Massage me a little harder.
[man 2] Who won?
This guy here.
[indistinct chattering]
Emerson?
[in English] Emerson, I'm so sorry.
We offer our condolences.
[in English] This is my sister-in-law,
Martina, and her son, Gavin.
- [in English] Condolence.
- [in English] My condolences.
[suspicious music playing]
[Emerson] Thank you for your sympathy.
[dramatic stinging]
- Um…
- You're Red's wife?
[dramatic sting]
[in English] Uh, I'm so sorry
for your loss.
[in English] I can only imagine
how tragic this must be for you.
Especially the way Tonet died.
[in English] She was such a lovely girl.
[Emerson] Yes, it was an accident. She…
She lost too much blood and then…
organ failure.
Will you sue? The mall?
Because she died on the premises, right?
Hmm, we haven't thought about that yet.
Auntie, excuse me.
All right.
[music swells]
Ah, sorry…
I just got distracted by your bag.
It's beautiful.
[in English] Oh, thank you!
[in English] It's my, uh, favorite one,
my lucky bag.
Your favorite?
But it looks like…
like something's missing.
It looks a little damaged.
It seems like it's missing a stud,
like… this?
It looks like it might fit. Let's see if--
[Martina, in English]
I don't-- I don't think that's gonna fit.
This brand has
a lot of knockoffs being sold.
- [Atoy] Ah. Is that so?
- [Martina titters]
[in English] Um, I'm just
gonna get a drink. Excuse me.
[tense music playing]
[Atoy] Oh?
Where were you all day yesterday?
Were you at a mall?
The same mall
where Tonet had her accident?
[in English] Shopping?
[intense music playing]
Wait--
Hold on. What's happening here?
- [Paldo] Atoy.
- [in English] Let me go.
[in English] Why are you asking me
such things?
Nothing. I'm just curious. Just asking.
I wasn't at the mall yesterday. Okay?
- You weren't shopping?
- [in English] No.
Where were you?
[Martina, in English] What is this about?
[suspicious music playing]
Because I saw this
at the place where Tonet had her accident.
Here.
It just looks a bit… similar…
Maybe it just looks alike, right?
Huh? Because it could be this.
Oh, it could be this.
Maybe it's just coincidence, right?
Who knows? We don't know.
[dramatic sting]
And your perfume.
Oh. [sniffs]
Your favorite too?
It smells good.
[grunting]
What do you guys think?
What about you? What do you think?
Was Tonet's death really an accident?
Huh? What do you think?
- [Paldo] What's going on here?
- [scoffs]
You know, I want to be offended.
But it's funny.
[in English] This is a bit silly
and pathetic, don't you think?
Don't call us pathetic!
[tense music playing]
Atoy's instincts are never wrong.
So, where were you?
Were you there, where my sister died?
Huh? Were you the one
who killed my sister?
[Atoy] Emerson!
Did you kill my sister?! You killed--
- You killed my sister?!
- [clamoring]
- [Martina, in English] Let me go!
- Ha?! You monster!
You killed my sister!
[in English] How dare you!?
I could sue you for assault!
- [Paldo] Stop it!
- [Emerson] Do it!
You have no shame!
Did you come here just to make sure
that my sister was killed?!
I came here to respectfully
offer condolences!
[in English] And then, you're gonna
accuse me of such things?!
[in English] Over what evidence?!
My perfume and my bag?!
What are you, psychic?!
Enough. Enough of that!
[woman] You know what, miss? Just leave!
[people] Yes! Leave! Leave now!
- [clamoring]
- Stop it! Enough already.
- [Emerson] Not a criminal?
You are a criminal! I'll prove it!
I'll have you jailed, you animal!
[in English] Well, you'd better get
yourself a good lawyer then!
- [clamoring]
- [intense music playing]
[people] Criminal! Criminal!
[dramatic stinging]
- Get out of here!
- Hey!
Shut up! What's wrong with you?!
Don't get involved.
That's my boss' wife!
- [Gavin] Karla.
- What are you doing here?
Offering condolences.
Why didn't you tell me?
I only found out from my aunt.
It's okay.
I know you were on a date with Cathy.
[in English] Sorry.
[in English] I should have
been there for you.
But we're still friends, right?
- Let me help you with that.
- No, don't.
- [Gavin] No, I want to help.
- It's okay. No--
- No, it's okay.
- Hey.
Look what you've done.
- [Gavin sighs]
- [sighs]
- I already said don't.
- Give it to me.
[pensive music playing]
Hey, boy! So, it's you, huh?
I saw you earlier.
You were with those two women
who killed Tonet!
We didn't do anything wrong.
Tonet was my friend.
Psst, make him leave.
Make him leave, right now!
Miss Fely, he didn't do anything.
Leave! Get out of here!
Go!
That nuisance.
Mom, why do they think
you did something to Tonet?
[in English] I honestly don't know, Gavin.
Maybe they just can't accept
the way your friend died.
[in English] You can go ahead now.
[somber music playing]
[tense music playing]
And you…
literally just stood there
and did nothing,
while people ganged up on me.
That's on you, though.
If you were not making excuses,
you were acting angry.
[in English] Wow!
Thank you for that, Audrey.
It's just the two of us here.
Tell me the truth.
Where were you yesterday?
[in English] I was at my office!
- At Bahay Kayakap!
- Really?
Then why was your bag stud found
where Tonet died?
[in English] I don't know, Audrey!
I'm not the only one
in the world with bag studs!
[in English] I don't believe you.
Why would I kill Tonet?
What's my motivation behind that?!
You were the last person she talked to
before she went to the mall!
[in English] Oh my God, Audrey!
You're acting like Atoy!
Now you think you're a detective?!
[in English] I'm not a criminal!
[in English] But you're married to one!
I wouldn't be surprised
if you're just like my brother!
Maybe even worse,
because you pretend to be innocent!
[in English] How dare you?!
[grunting]
[Martina, in English]
I really, really hate you!
[grunting and clamoring]
- [Red, in English] Enough! Stop!
- [Dmitri, in English] Enough! Stop!
- You're not my family!
- [grunts]
What are you two fighting about?!
[in English] She's accusing me of killing
some girl that I don't even know!
That Atoy just stirred things up,
and she believed him!
[suspicious music playing]
You believe Atoy more than her?
Compared to you two? Yes!
Because killing isn't new to this family!
- Audrey, my child!
- Stupid!
Audrey!
Whatever happened before, that was then!
It's over! We've changed!
Maybe you've changed, Dad.
I don't know about the others.
So, I'm a murderer?
Prove it! Prove it!
[in English] Your reaction
just confirms it.
- You're stupid!
- [in English] Red, stop it!
[in English] Stop this nonsense!
Dad, it's not nonsense if somebody died!
[tense music playing]
[Red] Then sue me!
Go ahead! Don't just keep talking!
I said enough already!
[Red] Stop siding with her all the time!
It's like we never did anything right!
Stupid! Let's go!
[intense music playing]
[Red] Why did you even fight with them?
[Martina grunts] They were already
saying harsh words!
[in English] You know what?
Audrey is no longer my concern.
[in English] It's-- It's that Atoy.
[sighs]
[in English] You know,
you asked me to go to that wake,
and I just ended up
looking stupid and guilty!
You shouldn't have made me go!
Let it go.
What's important is we know
what Atoy is thinking.
I can handle that.
Not just wait for the police
to pick you up.
[mysterious music playing]
[in English] So, what
are you gonna do? Hmm?
The evidence Atoy
gathered against you is weak.
The problem is Audrey.
[in English] Your sister hates us.
[in English] She'll believe
anything that's against us.
But if we can control
what Audrey thinks about you,
she could influence Atoy
to stop targeting you, right?
[in English] Hon, you don't know that.
Well, let's try.
What's important is you look like…
an innocent victim.
The evidence. We need to divert it.
[in English] Okay.
[electronic blipping]
[tense music playing]
[in English] That Atoy
is biased against Red.
What if he's wrong?
I'm serious. I'll really file
a case against her.
What I don't understand is…
UP NEXT
…if it's true, then what's her motive?
Was Martina at the office the other day?
[in English] Around 12 p.m. onwards?
[Ria] That's the magic of AI.
Ma'am, add to my salary, okay?
- Promise me that.
- Of course.
Oh, that matches exactly
what we saw Martina carrying,
so she really can't deny it.
[in English] Highly suggestive,
but it does not rise to the level
of establishing criminal liability.
Suspicion alone is insufficient.
Looks like Attorney is right, 'Son.
I wish you hadn't told me your suspicions,
so I wouldn't have hoped for nothing.
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias